My name is Deanna Gutierrez and I'm a high school teacher in San Jose.
Some of the pros of being a high school teacher are your emotional commitment to your students and the incredible rewards that you get when they succeed.
Also summer vacation.
Everybody knows teachers love this and also the opportunity to be your own boss.
In your classroom you rule and that is a great plus.
And you can tailor the curriculum usually to fit your talents and the way that the information will come easiest to your students.
Some of the cons of the profession are the salary.
Especially if you have a family.
Living on a teachers salary can be challenging.
Another drawback is the long hours.
You do have summer vacations and your day technically ends at 3:00 but what they don't tell you is you will be most likely bringing work back.
Grading either in your classroom or at home.
And you will be working on the weekends.
But it will be, hopefully, a labor of love.
And the last con would be the administrative red tape and dealing with principals and maybe co-teachers that don't share the same vision you do and just being true to yourself and to your students.
My name is Deanna Gutierrez and I'm a high school teacher in San Jose.